I've been thinking a lot lately about workaholics.
We live in a society that normalizes working
instead of doing the work.
So ask yourself, do you forsake your family
or like personal time, holidays, et cetera,
for the sake of work?
Do you tell yourself that this work that you're doing
is the fortifying grounding of who you are
do you tell yourself that you have to invest everything
in this work because it is everything?
Because baby, that's not a lot like an addict.
It's an addict.
Addiction essentially, essentially,
it's much deeper than this,
but essentially is not just a physical thing,
but then there are, of course, psychosomatic addictions
where you are using something to deal with anxiety.
And a lot of us use work to avoid.
We use work to avoid creating bonds.
We use work to avoid accountability.
We use work to avoid commitment.
And it doesn't just mean like commitment
to like a romantic relationship.
It can mean even commitment to yourself.
So something to ask yourself
because it could be in the way of your joy
and it doesn't have to be.
But I'm fine.